A Guide to the Rockefeller University records, Director, Herbert Spencer Gasser, Biographical Material, Series 6 FA814
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Biographical material, 6; 22.2 Cubic Feet 45 boxes, 4 volumes, 2 packages.
  - Laboratory photographs; prints of microphotos (Box 22)
    - Pig olfactory fibers. Differentiation of levels P81 a series 1-4; 1 lowest down; 4 closest to [see note book], 1953 April (Box 22, Folder 11)
    - Pig olfactory nerve, 1953 April (Box 22, Folder 12)
      - P81 a levels 1-4
      - P81 b level 1,2,3, Kos
      - P81 L level 4
    - Cat olfactory lobe PP block 1, 1953 May (Box 22, Folder 13)
    - Cat olfactory lobe; some dendrites fiber layers; mitral cell; glomerulus; outer flexiform, 1953 July (Box 22, Folder 14)
    - Rabbit Jacobson Kos, 1954 October (Box 22, Folder 15)
    - Cat Jacobson Kos, 1954 July (Box 22, Folder 15)
    - Rabbit olfactory Kos, 1954 November (Box 22, Folder 16)
    - Rabbit spheno palatine Kos (Box 22, Folder 16)
  - Laboratory photographs; prints of microphotos
    - Pig olfactory epithelium, 1954 January 1 (Box 23, Folder 1)
    - Pig olfactory epithelium, 1954 January 2 (Box 23, Folder 2)
    - C sheath series, 1954 (Box 23, Folder 3)
    - Lobster nerve (Box 23, Folder 4)
    - Cat olfactory Palade set B; cat olfactory Kos; Kos collodium, 1954 February (Box 23, Folder 5)
    - March Pig olfactory membrane nose onFormvar coating, 1954 (Box 23, Folder 5)
    - Bee antenna, 1953 (Box 23, Folder 6)
    - long distal antenna, 1954 (Box 23, Folder 6)
    - Bee olfactory near head ganglia; stalk near head, 1955 (Box 23, Folder 6)
    - Frog sciatic C fibers, 1955 (Box 23, Folder 7)
    - Bull frog drc skin nerve (Box 23, Folder 7)
    - Rat nasal mucosa Palade #684, 1954 May 1955 June (Box 23, Folder 8)
    - Cat olfactory mucous membrane Palade #648, #653, 1954 May 1955 June (Box 23, Folder 9)
  - Laboratory photographs; prints of microphotos
    - Medullated; high magnification C pictures saphenous block of sheath series, undated (Box 24, Folder 1)
    - Medullated longitudinal saphenous C Schwann, 1954 November-December (Box 24, Folder 2)
    - Pike olfactory peripheral end and near mucosa, 1954 June 2 (Box 24, Folder 3)
    - Pike olfactory nerves 3-4 mm from epithelium, 1954 June 18 (Box 24, Folder 4)
    - Pickeral olfactory fibers II A, 1954-1955 (Box 24, Folder 5)
    - Assorted extra prints olfactory (Box 24, Folder 6)
    - Assorted extra prints olfactory (Box 24, Folder 7)
  - Laboratory photographs; prints of microphotos (Box 25)
    - Nasal mucosa pH 7.8 cat Palade, 1955 January (Box 25, Folder 1)
    - Cat olfactory pH 7.8 #620, 1955 January (Box 25, Folder 2)
    - Pig olfactory Kos cross section, 1955 February (Box 25, Folder 2)
    - Prints of sections from which the areas of the Schwann sheath of the olfactory nerve was measured, 1955 January (Box 25, Folder 3)
    - Pig Kos section number bipolar cells/unit area (Box 25, Folder 3)
    - Palade pH series on saphenous (Box 25, Folder 4)
      - 325 1% OsO₄ in 21M sucrose pH = 4.70
      - 324 1% OsO₄ in H₂O [IJ (unbuffered hypotonic 0.039M. OsO₄)
      - 317 1% OsO₄ isotonic (pH+7.2 sucrose) buffered
      - 262 1% OsO₄ isotonic (sucrose) unbuffered pH6.30
      - 261 1% OsO₄ buffered pH+7.35
    - Palade pH series of sural cat (Box 25, Folder 5)
      - 332 1% OsO₄ buffered pH 7.30
      - 331 1% OsO₄ buffered pH 6.30
      - 330 1% OsO₄ buffered pH 5.30
    - Lamellated sheaths. Cat sural longitudinal Kos 21 hours. Rat cross section Kos, cut at 8 clicks, 1956 May 3 (Box 25, Folder 6)
    - Rabbit cervical sympathetic, 1956 November (Box 25, Folder 7)
    - University of London. Department of Anatomy (Robertson, operator), 1957 (Box 25, Folder 8)
    - University of London. Department of Anatomy (Robertson, operator) Schmidt-Lanterman cleft, undated (Box 25, Folder 9)
  - Microphotographs arranged in various groups. Some slides of varying sizes; some strips; arranged as much as possible by dates and description (Box 26)
    - nerve #3: no. 1-3: nerve #4: no. 4-11 (6 lacking), 1946-1947 (Box 26, Folder 1)
    - 8 c fibers, cat 1a, b, 2, 3a, 3b, 4a, 4b, 10 4 nerve #1 7, 2 (10), 12, 1948 (Box 26, Folder 2)
    - box 3 rat saphenous. 7 phase microphotographs Cat fibers, undated (Box 26, Folder 3)
    - microphoto prints (each labeled), 1951 (Box 26, Folder 4)
    - strips, 1951 (Box 26, Folder 5)
      - Latex ref
      - Nerve 3-C 1-28
      - 6 strips longitudinal hypogastric
      - 1 strip splenic
      - 9 strips saphenous
    - strips, 1955 (Box 26, Folder 6)
      - 2 cat nerve frontal, vertical root
      - 3 cat V cross section
      - 2 rat block # 1
      - 1 Rabbit cervical symp
      - 1 unlabeled
    - series 1 and 2 nos. 1-10 single shots, 1959 (Box 26, Folder 7)
      - 1 undated
    - 8 pieces, 1960 (Box 26, Folder 8)
      - Calibration
      - Fiber 1-6
      - Nerve bunches to vastric (level within psoas)
    - Cat peroneal (3 and calibration), 1961 (Box 26, Folder 9)
    - Spencer (5 described on each), undated (Box 26, Folder 10)
    - (3 cat lower thoracic ventral root), 1959 (Box 26, Folder 11)
  - Glass microphotoqraphs, 5 × 7, individually labeled (Box 27)
    - Omnic-latex x 2375 1-19 (some missing), undated
    - 1-2, 4-6, undated
    - glyptal B size control, undated
      - glyptal B3 1, 13-19
      - glyptal B3 2, 6-12
      - glyptal B3 4, 20-22 size control fasc. II and 1st nerve fasc. 1, undated
    - 120-7, 2a-25, undated
  - Glass microphotographs, 5 × 7, individually labeled (Box 28)
    - 36056, 1944
    - 120, 121, 170, 1948
    - 170-7 C-P, 1948
    - 171,179,455,456,459, 1948
    - 545 (1,23,5-15, 18-21,23-39 Nerve Fasc. 1), 1948 May 10
  - Glass microphotographs, 5 × 7, individually labeled (Box 29)
    - 47-76,78-80,82, undated
    - 1-2,4-8,10-14,16-26, undated
  - Glass microphotographs, 5 × 7, individually labeled (Box 30)
    - 27, 30-41-45, undated
    - 224-7, undated
    - 546, 585, 1948
    - 713,798,1000, 1016-1017, 1949
    - 2281,2292,2293,2294,2304, 1951
    - 5439,5454,5455,5485, 1955
  - 5 × 7" negatives
    Includes copies made of microphotos, photos of impulse movements, action currents, potentials, also composite diagrams, charts and illustrations used in publications.
    Arranged in chronological order and grouped by years. Numbered consecutively by photographers.
    - 25805,25978, 1935 (Box 31, Folder 1)
    - 25995-26002,26016-26017,26025-26026,26029-26030,26038, 26055,26063,26156,26277-26278,26299-26300,26317, 26334-26336, 26345-26348,26366-26367,26380-26381, 26384, 26478,26485-26492, 26497-26499, 26521-26522, 26532-26534, 26546, 26550, 26618, 26736, 26753-26764, 26770, 26875-26878, 26946, 27035-27036, 27112-27115, 27120-27121, 1936 (Box 31, Folder 1)
    - 8 × 10 negatives 26944, 26945, 26947, 27037, 1936 (Box 31, Folder 2)
    - 27205-27207, 27218, 27223, 27274-27275, 27391, 27304-27306, 27398, 27538, 27539, 27541, 27550-27551, 27557, 27560-27570, 27597, 27661, 27679, 27807, 27819-27821, 27835-27836, 28161-28162, 28300-28301, 28337-28338, 28341-28342, 1937 (Box 31, Folder 3)
    - 8 × 10 27808, 30358, 1937-1939 (Box 31, Folder 4)
    - 28565, 28678-28684, 28695, 29447-29448, 1938 (Box 31, Folder 5)
    - 29888, 29907, 30324-30325, 30361-30365, 30703-30705, 30716, 30722-30732, 30755, 31043, 31088, 31177, 1939 (Box 31, Folder 5)
    - Dr. Renshaw 31180-31181, 31552-31553 31764, 32175, 32321, 33212, 1939-1940 (Box 31, Folder 6)
    - 31324-31326, 31331-31332, 31341, 31318, 31438-31440, 31445-31446, 31477, 31481-31482, 31491, 31554-31555, 31558, 31763, 31765, 31990, 31992, 32146-32149, 32174, 32292-32296, 32304, 32432-32435, 32437, 1940 (Box 31, Folder 7)
    - 1941 32448, 32842-32845 33197-33203 (Dr. Renshaw) 33204-33210 (Dr. Renshaw) 33211, 33213-33218, 33289-33290, 33496 (Box 31, Folder 8)
    - 33671, 33686-33687, 34236, 34581, 34591, 34593, 34600-34601, 34603, 34900, 1942 (Box 31, Folder 9)
    - 34901-34902, 36190, 36193-36194, 1943 (Box 31, Folder 9)
    - 36475, 36498-36499, 36505-36506, 36526, 36572, 36573, 36597, 36614, 36616, 1945 (Box 31, Folder 9)
  - Negatives
    The following group of negatives includes with each negative the order information from Graphic Services which gives a description of the photographic technique used.
    - 30, 201-202, 549 photos of "Queenie" (a dog) and a copy negative of a legend from a book illus, 1948 (Box 31, Folder 10)
      Also includes illustrations from 1947 report to the Corporation.
    - 1036, 1040-1042, 1060, 1204-1205, 1245, 1269, 1292 1298, 1322-1323, 1949 (Box 31, Folder 10)
    - 1455, 1495, 1497, 1837, 1903, 1950 (Box 31, Folder 11)
      Includes Physiology scientific report.
    - 2994, 1951 (Box 31, Folder 11)
    - 3434, 3472, 3491, 3527, 3658, 3671, 3690, 3707, 3826, 1952 (Box 31, Folder 11)
  - 5 x 7" negatives
    - 3922, 2931, 3951, 4085, 4281, 4356, 4358, 4362, 1953 (Box 32, Folder 1)
    - 4922, 4925, 4928, 4940, 5120, 5132, 5144, 5223, 1954 (Box 32, Folder 1)
    - 5230, 5282-5283, 5377, 5395, 5402, 5417, 5438, 5573, 5699, 1955 (Box 32, Folder 2)
    - 5753, 5754, 5863-5866, 6005, 6024, 6029, 6044, 6616, 6625, 6629, 6695, 1956 (Box 32, Folder 2)
    - 6926, 7004, 7009, 7051, 7123, 7204, 7290, 7340, 7361, 7362, 7443, 7527, 7677, 1957 (Box 32, Folder 3)
    - 8842-8843, 9767-9768, 1959 (Box 32, Folder 3)
  - 3 x 4" lantern slides, 3 × 4 lantern slides (Box 33)
    Some prepared from electromicroscopic negatives; some prepared from charts used in various publications. Boxed in groups as follows:
    - 4 28339, 30363, 30365, 34601, undated
    - 1950-1951, 5 slides
    - 1952-1953, 5 slides
    - 1953, 4 slides
    - Untitled, 7 slides
    - 1955 January-July, 17 slides
    - 1955 September-December, 20 slides
    - 1956, 7 slides
    - 1957 January-April, 6 slides
    - 1957 June-November, 7 slides
    - 3 packages of engraving plates used in JOURNAL OF GENERAL PHYSIOLOGY v. 43, no. 5 May 1960
  - Specimens, embedded (mainly in paraffin); some slides, in separate envelopes, 1951-1960
    Arranged in consecutive numbering, by years Description of the specimen on each envelope.
    - 1951, 13 envelopes (blue, not numbered) (Box 34)
    - 16-67 (lacks 27, 33-35), 1951 (Box 34)
    - 68-181 (lacks 86-89), 1952 (Box 34)
    - 182-216, 1953 (Box 34)
    - 1954, 28 envelopes numbered a-x (Box 34)
    - 1954, 2 envelopes dated, not numbered (Box 34)
    - 1954, 16 envelopes numbered bb-tt (Box 34)
    - 1955, 32 envelopes numbered uu-zz; a3-w3 (Box 34)
    - 1956, 23 envelopes numbered y3-z3; a4-m4; n5-s5 (Box 35)
    - 1957, 9 envelopes numbered u5-z5; a6-d6 (Box 35)
    - 1958, 11 envelopes numbered g6-s6 (Box 35)
    - 1959, 6 envelopes numbered t6-z6; a7 (Box 35)
    - 1960, 2 envelopes numbered c7-d7 (Box 35)
    - undated, 2 envelopes (Box 35)
    - untitled, 6 undated blue envelopes label information indicated on envelope (Box 35)
  - Slides of microscopic sections in box
    - E.M. Grids in capsules A16OOx 1951-1955. Labeled on inside of box cover (also numbered #1) (Box 36 - Series 6)
    - Guinea Pig slides, special stains, 2/16/1956 (Box 37)
      Each slide labeled (also numbered #2).
    - Rabbit, cat, pig, frog slides 1954-1957. Each slide labeled and also inside of box cover (also numbered #3) (Box 38)
    - Gp #2 slides, 4/3/1956 (Box 39 - Series 6, Box 40 - Series 6, Box 41 - Series 6)
      Each slide labeled. These boxes form 1,2,3 of a group (also numbered #4,#5,#6).
    - Cat spinal cord slides 1955. Slides of cat 5th, 1956 (also numbered #7) (Box 42)
    - Assorted group of slides (Box 43)
      Colloidin preparations of 6-day mice. Pig mucous membrane, 1955. Cat cord, undated.
    - Early slides (black box): Dating and labeling not clear and subjects not clearly identified (Box 44)
  - Copy prints of microfilm records, Box 11. Prints by Mr. Jim Williams, 1982 (Box 45)